In this lesson, we found the probability that
في هذا الدرس، وجدنا احتمالية أن
a coin would land on heads k times out of n flips.
عملة معدنية سوف تهبط على رؤوس k من دون تقلب.
If the probability of heads for the coin is p,
إذا كان احتمالية الرؤوس لهذه العملة هو p،
we get the following formula for the probability that the number of heads will be k.
فإننا نحصل على الصيغة التالية لاحتمالية أن يكون عدد الرؤوس k.
The first half is n factorial over n minus k factorial times k factorial.
النصف الأول هو عامل n على n ناقص عامل k مضروبًا في k.
This part keeps track of the total number of ways
يقوم هذا الجزء بتتبع إجمالي عدد الطرق التي
we can get k heads and n total flips of the coin.
يمكننا من خلالها الحصول على رؤوس k وإجمالي تقلبات العملة n.
For example, if we were looking at three heads and four flips,
على سبيل المثال، إذا نظرنا إلى ثلاثة رؤوس وأربعة تقلبات،
we could get this set of flips,
يمكننا الحصول على هذه المجموعة من التقلبات،
or this set, or this set, or this set.
أو هذه المجموعة، أو هذه المجموعة، أو هذه المجموعة.
There are four possible ways we can get three heads out of four flips.
هناك أربع طرق ممكنة يمكننا من خلالها الحصول على ثلاثة رؤوس من أربعة تقلبات.
This part of the formula keeps track of
يتتبع هذا الجزء من الصيغة
how many possible ways we can get these k heads and n flips.
عدد الطرق الممكنة التي يمكن أن نحصل من خلالها على رؤوس k وتقلبات n.
In this case four.
في هذه الحالة أربعة.
Each one of these ways have the following probability of event occurring.
كل واحد من هذه الطرق لديه الاحتمالية التالية لحدث ما.
P to the k times 1 minus p to the n minus k. The p
P إلى مضاعفات k 1 ناقص p إلى n ناقص k. p
to the k keeps track of the probability associated with the number of heads.
إلى k يتتبع الاحتمالية المرتبطة بعدد الرؤوس.
And this part keeps track of the probability associated with the number of tails.
وهذا الجزء يتتبع الاحتمالية المرتبطة بعدد الذيول.
Altogether, this formula gives
تعطي هذه الصيغة تمامًا
the probability of what's called the binomial distribution.
احتمالية ما يسمى التوزيع ثنائي الحد.
You've now seen how you can take very large experiments with
لقد رأيت الآن كيف يمكنك أن تأخذ تجارب كبيرة جدًا
many coin flips and compute the probability that
مع العديد من تقلبات العملة وحساب احتمالية أن
the coin will land heads a certain number of times with this formula.
العملة سوف تسقط الرؤوس بعدد معين من المرات مع هذه الصيغة.
Although the examples in this lesson use coin flips,
على الرغم من أن الأمثلة الواردة في هذا الدرس تستخدم تقلبات العملة،
you can really perform these calculations with any events that have two outcomes.
يمكنك بالفعل إجراء هذه الحسابات مع أي أحداث لها نتيجتين.
Does a customer buy or not?
هل العميل يبيع أم لا؟
Is a transaction fraud or not?
هل المعاملة احتيالية أم لا؟
Or if a coin flip is heads or tails.
أو إذا كان تقلب العملة عبارة عن رؤوس أو ذيول.
Binomial distributions are used to give us insight about all of these.
يستخدم التوزيع ثنائي الحد ليمنحنا الرؤية حول كل هذه.
Later in the course,
لاحقًا في هذه الدورة التدريبية،
you will explore large experiments again using the normal distribution.
سوف تستكشف تجارب كبيرة مرة أخرى باستخدام التوزيع الطبيعي.
But first, let's move on to
لكن دعونا أولًا ننتقل
conditional probability where events are no longer independent.
إلى الاحتمال الشرطي حيث لم تعد الأحداث مستقلة.
Let's explore cases where the outcome of
دعونا نستكشف الحالات التي يمكن أن تؤثر
an event can affect the outcome of the events that follow.
فيها نتيجة الحدث على نتيجة الأحداث التالية.